Hello, my name is J. I'm
大家好 我叫 J
a content developer at Udacity, and today we'll
我是优达学城的一名内容开发工程师
be talking about a powerful RNN technique called sequence
今天我将讨论一个非常强大的 RNN 技巧
to sequence.
叫做序列到序列
In a previous lesson, Andrew Trask
在上一节课中
showed us how to do sentiment analysis
Andrew Trask 讲解了如何使用
using normal feedforward neural networks.
常规前馈神经网络进行情感分析
The network was able to learn how
神经网络能够了解
positive or negative each word was, and could
每个单词的语气是积极的还是消极的
tell if a sequence as a whole had positive or negative things
并能够判断整个句子对讲述的主体
to say about its subjects.
持正面态度还是负面态度
We start running into issues, however,
但是当我们想要制作更复杂的模型
when we want to do a little bit more advanced models that deal
以便处理语言和序列数据时
with language and in sequential data.
我们遇到了问题
Let's take an example.
我们看个示例
So the authors of the "Deep Learning" book
深度学习图书的作者
present the following example to showcase this.
给出了下面的示例
So say we have these two sentences,
假设有下面两句话
I went to Nepal in 2009, and in 2009, I went to Nepal.
“I went to Nepal in 2009”和“In 2009, I went to Nepal”
If we train a model to read these inputs
如果我们对一个模型进行训练
and extract the year that the person went to Nepal,
要求该模型读取这些输入内容并提取出此人去尼泊尔的年份
we would want them to recognize 2009
我们肯定希望将 2009
as the piece of information we're looking for, right?
看做我们要获取的信息 对吧
So if we actually train a regular feedforward neural
如果我们训练一个普通前馈神经网络去处理这个任务
network on this task, it will have separate parameters
它将对每个输入特征
for each input feature.
分配单独的参数
So technically it would have to learn all the rules of language
理论上来说 它需要单独学习
separately at each position in the input sentiments.
输入句子中每个位置的语言规则
Then in another previous lesson, Matt
在之前的另一节课中
showed us our first recurrent neural network, RNN.
Matt 向我们展示了第一个循环神经网络 (RNN)
Recurrent nets are a powerful class of neural networks
循环神经网络是一类强大的神经网络
that deal with sequential data.
负责处理序列数据
They are especially suited for language and translation tasks,
它们非常适合处理语言和翻译任务
because they can extend to sequences of any length.
因为它们可以扩展至任何长度的序列
But more importantly, they share their parameters
更重要的是 它们可以共享
across different timesteps.
不同时间步长的参数
So when they do learn a language model,
所以当它们学会一个语言模型后
they do it a lot more efficiently
它们的学习速度比
than a traditional feedforward network would.
传统前馈神经网络要快很多
Now when we say sequential data, we
当我们提到序列数据时
can be referring either to the input
可以指代模型的输入数据
or the output of the model.
或输出数据
I guess you might have seen this diagram before.
我猜你之前可能见过这个图表
This is from the incredible essay about RNNs
该图表摘自 Andrej Karpathy 的
by Andrej Karpathy.
精彩 RNN 论文
And it shows different kinds of RNNs
图中展示了不同类型的 RNN
that are suited for different types of tasks.
它们适合不同类型的任务
The sentiment analysis RNN that Matt showed us is this one.
这个是 Matt 展示的情感分析 RNN
It reads a sequence of words, and then outputs
它读取单词序列
just a single value.
然后输出一个值
It's a many to one network.
也就是多对一网络
But if you want to build a chat bot or a translation service,
但是如果你想构建聊天机器人或翻译服务
you're going to have both sequential inputs
则需要具有序列输入
and sequential outputs.
和序列输出
So that's going to be on the many to many side
也就是该图表右侧的
of the diagram there to the right.
多对多模式
So we have these two options.
有这两种模式
So if we use a single RNN, then we
如果我们使用单个 RNN
are forced to output at most as many vectors as we input.
那么就需要输出最多和输入一样多的向量
And that wouldn't work for a chat bot.
这对聊天机器人来说不可行
We also want our model to take in the entire input
我们还希望在开始生成回复之前
before we start generating the response.
模型能传入整个输入
So this is not appropriate for our needs.
所以不能满足我们的需求
But then if you look at this one,
但是再看看这个模式
there's this other many to many RNN.
也是多对多 RNN
In 2014, luckily, two RNN architectures
幸运的是 在 2014 年出现了两种 RNN 结构
were introduced that can map a sequence of any length
可以将任何长度的序列映射到
to another sequence of any length.
另一个任何长度的序列
The basic premise is that you use
基本原理是
two RNNS, one that reads the input sequence,
使用两个 RNN 一个读取输入序列
then hands over what it had learned
然后将所学的规律
to another RNN, which starts producing the output sequence.
发送给另一个 RNN 该 RNN 接着生成输出序列
In the next videos, we'll be looking more closely
在接下来的视频中 我们将详细了解这种模式
at the intuition and the major concepts of RNNs.
以及重要 RNN 概念
And we'll be also touching on the implementation
我们还将详细介绍
details in TensorFlow of sequence to sequence.
如何在 TensorFlow 中实现序列到序列模型
But before that, I just want you to think
但在此之前
about the incredible variety of tasks
请先思考下当你能够像这样训练网络后
that you can accomplish when you can teach a network like this.
网络可以完成的各种复杂任务